cordovalegacy19@gmail.com 425-802-4573

Lead Full Stack Developer

Skills

- Languages: React, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, Java, CSS, HTML, JQuery, Ajax, Jinja2
- Frameworks: NextJS, NodeJS, Redux, Tailwind, Express, Flask, Bootstrap, SASS, Framer Motion, MUI, Vite, GraphQL
- ORM: Mongoose, Prisma, Django
- Databases: MongoDB, MySQL (NoSQL & SQL)
- Tools: Git, Github, Heroku, Vercel, AWS EC2, AWS Lambdas, AWS Microservices, AWS Route-53, VSCode, Postman, Miro, Figma, Jira, Trello

Education

01/2023

S.M.E. Certification:

MERN/Python/Fundamentals

Colorado Technical University 09/2022

Certificate Of Graduation:

Software Development

Coding Dojo

Certificate Of Completion:

Redux Core & Redux Toolkit

Udemy

05/2023

Certificate Of Completion:

NextJS- V.13

Udemy

Professional Projects

- Portfolio: (https://nextjs13-cordovaportfolio.vercel.app/)
- 3BX:
- (https://www.booksbeatsbox.com)
- Search Engine: (https://nextjs13-googleclone.vercel.app/)
- AISOP OpenAI Games: (www.aisop.io)
- Legacy Builds, LLC: (www.legacybuildspc.com)
- IMDB Clone: (https://imdb-clonecordovalegacy.vercel.app/)
- Specialist in Probate: (https://glacialdawn-05023.herokuapp.com/)
- GitHub Projects: (https://github.com/cordovalegacy).

Brendan Cordova

Summary

LEAD FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Passionate Lead Full Stack Software Developer with a focus on problem solving and results. Over 3 years coding of experience and 5 years of computer hardware experience. Leads frontend projects on a variety of languages and frameworks such as TypeScript, React, NextJS, Framer-Motion, Tailwind CSS, and more. Mentors other developers on fundamentals and advanced topics. Dedicated Full Stack Engineer, with multiple years of work experience and contract experience.

Professional Experience

Books Beats Box - Lead Full Stack Developer

04/2023 - Current

- Manages both Backend and Frontend aspects of development process with a focus on the Frontend.
- Transforms wireframes from Figma into highly responsive, animated, data-driven applications.
- Builds out mobile and desktop applications.
- · Collaborates with DevOps team on AWS serverless back-ends.
- Leads in frontend projects in transforming wireframes and ideas into functional, highly user experience focused applications.
- Participates in design (UX/UI) with the design team in Figma.

Colorado Technical University - Software Engineer

08/2022 - Current

- Collaborates with development team on curriculum & learning platform
- Builds out digital tools to roll out to student learning and process optimization
- · Develops full-stack applications using MERN and Python/Flask/MySql
- Teaches classes of up to 80 students on modern coding languages, frameworks, and fundamentals
- Conducts hundreds of code review sessions
- Runs coding workshops: Git, GitHub, CSS, React, JavaScript, Python, TypeScript, and Tailwind CSS
- · Works on applications that pull in openAI functionality to create and optimize bots

Specialist In Probate - Software Developer

06/2021 - 05/2023

- · Worked to produce wireframes for website
- · Developed, updated, maintained, and deployed new additions to company code
- Built internal applications w/ ReactJS

Legacy Builds LLC - Software Developer

08/2020 - 05/2023

- Designed and deployed entire website using MongoDB, Express, React, and NodeJS, and AWS
- · Actively managed and maintained company code

GitHub - Personal Projects

- · 1300 Contributions
- · 190 Repositories